

MATTHEW CALLAHAN

Software Engineer | Phoenix, Arizona

EDUCATION



University of Wisconsin-Madison

Bachelor of Science, Geographic Information Systems

EXPERIENCE

Republic Services | Scottsdale, AZ | December 2018 - Present

Staff Engineer (management): May 2019 - Present

- Lead a team of developers and testers by prioritizing tasks, delegating duties, and guiding projects to successful and on-time delivery.
- Provide mentorship and technical training to developers department wide.
- Established and implemented a standard application architecture for greenfield development, allowing developers to rapidly begin coding and reducing the time needed to deliver a minimum viable product.
- Implemented unit test standards for the team and led effort to increase test coverage in all applications, reducing the number of production bugs.
- Authored coding conventions and style guide documents for developers and currently leading effort to refactor all applications to follow these guidelines.

Senior Developer: December 2018 - May 2019

- Developed enterprise GIS web applications which provided customer data mapping and route visualization tools to assist in waste disposal operations.
- Developed APIs and services which provided data and analysis functions to other development teams and applications throughout the company.
- Supported desktop development for GIS data analysis and batch data processing.
- Implemented a Git branching strategy and code review process for all application repositories, increasing team throughput and code quality.

Carvana | Tempe, AZ | February 2018 – December 2018

Software Engineer

- Primary job function was back end development to create and maintain the APIs and microservices which powered carvana.com using C#, .NET & .NET Core.
- Supported front end development to maintain and enhance a mobile responsive UI for vehicle inventory search engine (JavaScript ES6+, React & Redux).
- Implemented A/B testing to help drive data analytics and deliver the best UX.

CBRE | Tempe, AZ | March 2008 - February 2018

Application Developer: January 2011 - February 2018

- Developed web applications which provided mapping, site selection, and data analysis tools for real estate brokers and their clients using ASP.NET MVC.
- Developed desktop applications for GIS data processing and analysis using C#, .NET, WinForms, MapBasic, ArcGIS Pro .NET SDK, and Python.
- Administered on-prem servers (Windows Server, IIS, SQL Server, ArcGIS Server).

GIS Technician: March 2008 – January 2011

- Developed scripts and desktop GIS tools to automate data analysis tasks.
- Created custom maps and market research reports for brokerage staff, affording them the ability to make well informed decisions and best serve their clients.

ABOUT ME

My name is Matthew Callahan, and I am a player-coach in the software world: I enjoy writing code as well as leading my team and mentoring developers. I have over ten years of experience in software development and continuing to learn the ever-changing landscape of programming is my passion.

CONTACT

Email: matthew.callahan@outlook.com

Phone: 630-988-1555

Homepage: mfcallahan.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mfcallahan1

GitHub: github.com/mfcallahan

Blog: seesharpdotnet.wordpress.com

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Technology Associate: Developer

KEY SKILLS

Languages

C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python

Frameworks

.NET & .NET Core, Node.js, Angular, React, ArcGIS

Testing

NUnit, Jasmine, Mocha, Selenium

Dev Tools

Azure, Git, GitHub Actions, Jenkins, Splunk, SQL Server

resume ver 2021.02.1